Gethin Jones

Junior Software Developer

gethin.jones28@gmail.com | 07415 407 776 London | GitHub, Portfolio, LinkedIn

Personal Statement

My journey in tech began in 2014 sat in my shed pondering how technology could be used to control prosthetic limbs. This desire to help others was combined with a huge interest in the global scope of the web and how well-built web apps could spread awareness about important topics like climate change or assist users in their daily lives. After my first taste of JavaScript, making web apps became a much-enjoyed hobby, playing around with data visualisation and front-end development. My enthusiasm for problem-solving led me to take on full-stack JavaScript development, where I hope to apply my skills in a long-term position. A broad knowledge of topics related to digital experiences and their applied aesthetics continues to inspire my vision while creating solutions.

Technical Skills

Languages: HTML & CSS, JavaScript (ES6+) & TypeScript (Node.js and browser environments) **Front-End:** React.js, Next.js, React Native w/ Expo, UI Component Libraries, CSS Frameworks (Utility-first & Component-Based), Headless UI, CSS-in-JS

Back-End: Node.is, Express, SQL, PostgreSQL (PSQL), RESTful APIs

Testing: Test-Driven Development (TDD) with Jest and SuperTest, React Testing Library

Database Management: Design, query & optimisation of PostgreSQL databases, MongoDB, Firestore

Other Frameworks & Libraries: Meteor.js (leveraging Node.js and MongoDB), Three.js (data

visualisation), Cordova (mobile app development)

Git for version control | Agile development | Paired programming | Web Performance Optimisation | Responsive design (Media Queries, Flex-Box, CSS Grids) | CSS preprocessors | SEO

Projects

Theta Wave: Meditation timer made with React, MUI, WebGL and Firestore
NC Project Back End: Restful API - A robust back-end for a fictional news website (GitHub)
NC Project: Responsive front-end built using React with Joy UI for the fictional news website
NC Group Project: Parking app using TypeScript, React Native with Expo, Firebase, Tamagui, MapLibre
Ready To Work: Real-time web app created with Meteor, Node.js, MongoDB, BLAZE & Foundation
Data Visualisation: Interactive web app showing world sustainability data on a 3D globe with D3.JS

Professional Development

Junior Software Developer | Northcoders Software Development Bootcamp | Oct 24 - Mar 25 (Intensive JavaScript Development Bootcamp covering back-end and front-end)

- Developed scalable back-end systems with performance optimisation and modular code architecture
- Built RESTful APIs using Node.js and Express, ensuring best practices in web security and efficient data flow between the client and server
- Designed and implemented server-side logic for dynamic web applications, integrating both Firestore and PostgreSQL for robust data storage and retrieval
- Leveraged middleware in Express to handle authentication, request validation, and error handling
- Built responsive user interfaces using React.js, styled with modern CSS3 design
- Gained Testing and debugging skills with good knowledge of testing methodologies and tools
- Utilised Agile Development and teamwork skills in paired programming sprints

Other - The Odin Project, EPIC React, Udemy Full-Stack Web Development

Experience

Warehouse Assistant | London Bridge Books/ Booktrolls Warehouse | 2021 - 2024

- Exposure to a complex digital stock handling system in a large book warehouse
- Proven adaptability and ability to learn quickly in different situations and tasks
- Regularly achieved bonuses for maintaining excellent accuracy and efficiency

Stock Management - John Lewis | 2020-2021 | 2013-2015 (break for study + travel)

- Working for a large well-established business with exposure to various departments and stock flow
- Time Management Ability to switch tasks to meet the moving needs of the business
- Independent, driven and responsible work ethic regularly commended by management

Freelance Digital Designer | 2018-2020

- Professional Bespoke Website design for several small businesses and independent clients
- Strong communication skills listening to the needs of clients and explaining features
- Experience in creating solutions for a range of projects utilising APIs for custom music playback, complex CSS animations, effects and transitions, video backgrounds and media queries for responsive design

Web Content & Development Administrator | Perfect Document Creation | 2017-2019

- Versatility through Bulk Asset Creation, Social Media roles and Website Administration
- Precise attention to detail while in charge of data entry responsibilities for thousands of products
- Problem-solving ability and strong analytical skills to find effective solutions quickly

Previous experience available on request

Education

Brunel University | Digital Design Bsc | 2014 - 2018 | First Class Honors

Leaving a job building skateboards to pursue building web applications at age 22, I had clear goals and applied myself to the broad scope of topics covered*. My disciplined approach to learning earned me a first-class honors degree, an exhibit at the Young Designer of the Year Exhibition and skills that were an invaluable foundation to later becoming a full-stack developer.

*Key modules included: Web Design & Development | Server-side Development | Mobile Web Development | Programming for Digital Media | Data Modelling | Interaction Design and Usability (UI/UX) | Digital Design Theory | Digital Experiences | Business for Digital Creative Industries | Experimental Digital Futures | Marketing & Professional Development | Video Production | Design Practice | Applied Media Aesthetics | Graphics | 3D Design & Animation | Digital Photography

Hobbies and Interests

Travelling: Love to get immersed in culture - highlights have been trekking the Himalayas in Nepal, exploring Cercedilla in Madrid, Mountain villages in Mexico, the deserts of Hampi in India and Athens **Bouldering:** Keen climber when not working off my dad-bod since my little girl was born last year **Music:** Proud listener of almost anything and everything. Dabble in recording vocals for multiple genres (love a bit of classic boom-bap hip-hop). Amateur producer of weird music, largely drum and bass and DJ of varied vinyl or digital sets

Hiking and Wild camping: Spent 6 months working in Scotland and exploring hammock spots on a motorcycle

Skateboarding: Mostly to get around these days on my cruiser overtaking cyclists